<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ling Yao on Ling Yao&#39;s Personal Website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ling Yao on Ling Yao&#39;s Personal Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Teaching as a graduate student</title>
      <link>/collection/2025-06-04-teaching-as-a-graduate-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/2025-06-04-teaching-as-a-graduate-student/</guid>
      <description>In this video, I discuss the pros and cons of teaching during graduate school, how to find different types of teaching opportunities, and lessons I have learned from working as an instructor and a teaching assistant.
Thanks to Ryan McWay and Carmen Armas Montalvo for organizing the Applied Economics (APEC) Skills Series Workshop and for excellent video production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principles of Economics</title>
      <link>/talk/econ-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/econ-principles/</guid>
      <description>From February to May 2024, I taught Principles of Economics at St. Olaf College to two sections of students. Before this, I worked as a teaching assistant in designing an online version of the course at UMN in the Fall 2022 semester.
When I designed the course, I paid special attention to the before-class and after-class assignments to help students establish a consistent rhythm. Before classes, students would read a short article or a news piece related to the subject and briefly answer some reflection questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barbies Don&#39;t Say Sorry</title>
      <link>/blog/2023-09-07-barbies-don-t-say-sorry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 15:54:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2023-09-07-barbies-don-t-say-sorry/</guid>
      <description>I enjoyed watching Barbie the movie directed by Greta Gerwig. As I have been following the interviews and discussions around it, I ran into an interview of Margot Robbie, who played as Barbie. In the interview she shared a important lesson that she learned from watching the Barbie&amp;rsquo;s official YouTube channel. That is, swapping the preventive &amp;ldquo;sorry&amp;rdquo; for the word &amp;ldquo;thank you&amp;rdquo;. For example, instead of saying &amp;ldquo;sorry, I can&amp;rsquo;t do that&amp;rdquo;, say &amp;ldquo;thank you for understanding that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t do that&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agricultural mechanization and structural change</title>
      <link>/project/mechanization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/mechanization/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subjective life expectancy and pension participation</title>
      <link>/project/subjective-life-expectancy-and-pension-participation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/subjective-life-expectancy-and-pension-participation/</guid>
      <description>Featured image by Freepik</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Share tenancy and agricultural risk</title>
      <link>/project/sharecropping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/sharecropping/</guid>
      <description>Featured image by Freepik</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conservation agriculture in developing countries</title>
      <link>/project/conservation-ag/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/conservation-ag/</guid>
      <description>Featured image by Freepik</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Minnesota (unofficial) Beamer poster template</title>
      <link>/collection/2023-08-08-university-of-minnesota-unofficial-overleaf-poster-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/2023-08-08-university-of-minnesota-unofficial-overleaf-poster-template/</guid>
      <description>This template is originally forked from Anish Athalye&amp;rsquo;s gemini beamer poster template. To use it, click on the button at the top of this page and make a copy of the Overleaf project.
Colors and logo     I created a UMN beamer color theme to replace the genemi color theme, and named the color theme file in the root directory &amp;ldquo;beamercolorthemeumn.sty&amp;rdquo;. Among the UMN official colors, I used the UMN Maroon for title background and the UMN Gold for the main title.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduate level Econometrics</title>
      <link>/talk/grad-econometrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/grad-econometrics/</guid>
      <description>Econometrics was among the most challenge courses I took in college. Admittedly, terms like &amp;ldquo;asymptotic&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;parametric&amp;rdquo; were just too abstract. After taking two versions of this course from different institutions and being the teaching assistant for four instructors that taught this course, I would say that I have climbed up on the spiraling ladder of learning enough to be no longer scared of it. Perhaps the best way to learn it is through viewing the same thing from different angles, and my favorite angle is through Professor Joe Ritter&amp;rsquo;s data simulation and visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managerial Economics</title>
      <link>/talk/managerial-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/managerial-economics/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math review for new graduate students in applied economics</title>
      <link>/talk/math-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/math-review/</guid>
      <description>This was a 45-hours summer course that I taught remotely in 2020 during the COVID-19 pandemic. It offered new graduate students an opportunity to connect with each other and prepare for the core courses. Some of the students took the course during midnight while they were still restricted in their home country. Every year I am fascinated by how much students are devoted to learn, overcoming barriers of space and time, and even the crazy realities during the pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typography Styles &amp; Element Examples</title>
      <link>/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:27:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/elements/</guid>
      <description>Font Sizes   A A A A A A A A   6rem
(96px) 5rem
(80px) 3rem
(48px) 2.25rem
(36px) 1.5rem
(24px) 1.25rem
(20px) 1rem
(16px) .875rem
(14px)     Type Samples Head&amp;shy;line Sub&amp;shy;head&amp;shy;line Level 1 Heading One page to rule them all...well, not really. This page displays sample typography and page elements to illustrate their style. Things like headings and paragraphs showing the beautiful type scale, form elements, tabular data, and image layouts just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributors</title>
      <link>/contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contributors/</guid>
      <description>Thank you to all the folks who have contributed both technical and creative skills to this project:
   Desirée De Leon 🦒 (designed 5 of the custom color themes, made illustrations for the workshop, and provided general aesthetic feedback along the way)
   Garrick Aden-Buie 🧙‍♀️ (debugged headroom.js and lent his panelset.js code to the theme)
   Allison Horst 🐕 (awesome illustrations of campfires, seedlings, and evergreens, as well as my R Markdown hedgehog mascot 🦔)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
